Guide to the Emma Smith Diaries, 1819-1858
Department of Special Collections
Emma Smith Diaries,
1819-1858
Special Collections M0298
Smith, Emma, d.1858.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1978.
Biographical Note
Emma Smith was an Englishwoman who lived at Tring Park, Hertfordshire and Glenville near Southhampton in the nineteenth century. She made regular trips to Europe during her lifetime.
Scope and Content
Diaries, travel journals, and sketchbooks (1819-1855) providing a detailed and sustained account of Emma Smith's daily life. Also included are papers regarding disposal of her property, her funeral account, and a printed copy of MANUAL OF NOBILITY.
Container List
- 1. 1804The Manual of Nobility, small, red. (Box 1)
- 2. 1819Small green daily diary (Box 1)
- 3. 1819Small red diary and record book (expenses) (Box 1)
- 4. 1825Large red daily diary (Box 1)
- 5. 1826Small red daily diary (Box 1)
- 6. 1827Small brown daily diary (Box 1)
- 7. 1828Small red daily diary (Box 1)
- 8. 1829Mottled green with red binding daily diary (Box 1)
- 9. 1829White daily diary (Box 1)
- 10. 1832Blue book with initials M.S., journal and letters. (Box 1)
- 11. 1831-32Small brown, household expense book (Box 1)
- 12. 1832Small red expense book (Box 1)
- 13. 1834Small red diary and record of expenses (Box 1)
- 14. 1834Large green journal with daily diary entries. (Box 1)
- 15. 1835Small red daily diary (Box 1)
- 16. 1837Small red daily diary (Box 2)
- 17. 1838Small purple daily diary (Box 2)
- 18. 1838Small blue daily diary (Box 2)
- 19. 1838Large black journal with red binding and daily diary entries. (Box 2)
- 20. 1829Small red daily diary (Box 2)
- 21. 1840 Lett's diary No 9 with daily diary entries. (Box 2)
- 22. 1841Small red daily diary (Box 2)
- 23. 1842Blue daily diary (Box 2)
- 24. 1843Large green daily diary - Germany (Box 2)
- 25. 1843 Journal in Germany daily diary (Box 2)
- 26. 1843Blue daily diary (Box 2)
- 27. 1844Blue-grey Diary 1844 with daily entries (Box 2)
- 28. 1845Brown with gold, daily diary (Box 2)
- 29. 1845Red with gold daily diary (Box 3)
- 30. 1845Dark green with red spine daily diary 1845 (Box 3)
- 31. 1846Blue with red spine Diary 1846 daily diary b (Box 3)
- 32. 1847 and 1851Journal of tour of France (Box 3)
- 33. 1847Blue Diary 1847 daily diary (Box 3)
- 34. 1849Grey Diary 1849 daily diary (Box 3)
- 35. 1851Green Daily Rememberancer (Box 3)
- 36. 1853Small red daily diary (Box 3)
- 37. 1855Grey brown Lett's Diary #11 1855 (Box 3)
- 38. 1843Sketchbook with watercolors - Purple water-stained cover, large. (Box 3)
- 39. 1851Red Album with sketches, some water colors, large (Box 3)
- 40. Small mottled grey and blue journal by niece (Box 3)
- 41. Large mottled red and grey sketchbook Sketches E.S. (Box 4)
- 42. Small mottled brown with blue binding sketch book (Box 4)
- 43. Marbeled paper over boards with half-leather binding - sketchbook, large (Box 4)
- 44. Green and black sketchbook (Box 4)
- 45. Grey and black sketchbook Laura Maria Seymour 1854 (Box 4)
- 46. 1904Sketchbook, watercolours Alice Mary Fellows - 1904 (Box 4)
- 47. Marbleddpaper, soft cover, begun 1796 Frolicks several hands (Box 4)
- 48. Small red account book, nd,personal addresses, recipes, distances. (Box 4)
- 49. Loose papers and sketches., (Folder) (Box 4)